{"tossups": [{"question": "This non-Egyptian state was founded by Qutb al-Din Aibak, a Mamluk who succeeded Muhammad of Ghor. The general Zafar Khan established the breakaway Bahmani Sultanate after a revolt against this state. A member of the Tughlaq Dynasty, Muhammad, attempted to shift its capital to the Deccan Plateau. This state was defeated by Babur at the First Battle of Panipat, causing it to be succeeded by the Mughal Empire. For ten points, name this Muslim state that ruled much of India from a namesake city.", "answer": "<b> Delhi</b> Sultanate", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "On April 13, 2016, this player went 22 for 50 from the field, scoring 60 points against the Utah Jazz to end the worst season in franchise history and his career. This man, who won an Oscar in 2018 for Best Animated Short Film for<em> Dear Basketball</em>, scored 81 points against the Raptors in 2006. For ten points, name this shooting guard who won five NBA titles with the Los Angeles Lakers in the early 2000s.", "answer": "Kobe<b> Bryant</b> (prompt on Kobe)", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {}, {"question": "One essay concerning this region includes chapters named for the Ohio and Mississippi Valleys; that essay, which was originally introduced during the World\u2019s Columbian Exposition, formed the basis of Frederick Jackson Turner\u2019s thesis on this region. In 1890, the U.S Census Bureau stated that rapid western expansion had \u201cclosed\u201d this region. For ten points, name this region which was traditionally considered to be the Western United States.", "answer": "American<b> Frontier</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "This thinker wrote that religion was the result of an \u201coceanic feeling\u201d in one work, and in another work he analyzed the \u201cdeath drive.\u201d This author of<em> Civilization and its Discontents</em> and<em> Beyond the</em> <em>Pleasure Principle</em> theorized about the subconscious desire for one\u2019s mother, which he called the \u201cOedipus complex.\u201d For ten points, name this Austrian thinker who coined the terms \u201cId,\u201d \u201cego,\u201d and \u201csuperego,\u201dthe father of psychoanalysis.", "answer": "Sigmund<b> Freud</b> Page 1", "metadata": "Social Science - Social Science - Psychology"}, {}, {"question": "This event\u2019s participants clashed with Khamba rebels, who were escaping from a failed revolt in Tibet. This event\u2019s planners sought to link up with He Long after Mo Xiong brought news of an impending attack. Otto Braun\u2019s wish to travel east was overruled during this event\u2019s Zunyi Conference, which took place shortly before a crossing at Luding Bridge. Participants in this campaign narrowly escaped destruction from the Encirclement Campaigns by traveling north to Shaanxi. For ten points, name this 1934 military retreat undertaken by Mao Zedong\u2019s Chinese Communists.", "answer": "<b> Long March</b> (prompt on Chinese Civil War)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "This state\u2019s Pillar Mountain contains an antenna farm for communication between one of its islands and the mainland. The Knick arm is one branch of inlet that stretches to the most-populous city in this state that is the Cook Inlet. In 1964, more than 100 people in this state died in a tsunami triggered by a 9.2 magnitude earthquake on Good Friday; that earthquake devastated Kodiak and Prince William Sound. For ten points, name this US state that contains the Aleutian Islands and the city of Anchorage.", "answer": "<b> Alaska</b>", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {}, {"question": "Merchants in this city called<em> pochteca</em> were exempt from paying taxes, instead having to donate to a ritual feast each year. This city was home to the Templo Mayor, a massive complex located in the Sacred Precinct. A massacre at this city\u2019s \u201cGreat Temple\u201d led citizens to drive out Pedro de Alvarado as part of La Noche Triste. This city was founded after settlers saw an eagle atop a cactus with a snake in its mouth. Hernan Cortes conquered, for ten points, what capital of the Aztec Empire?", "answer": "<b> Tenochtitlan</b> Page 2", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "This man was named heir after the revolt of Casperius Aelianus. This man annexed the Nabataean Kingdom and captured Ctesiphon from the Parthians. His architect Apollodorus of Damascus built a massive bridge across the Danube as part of a war against Decebalus that ended with the capture of Sarmizegetusa. The forum and market built during his lifetime survive to today. This ruler celebrated his Dacian campaign with his namesake column. For ten points, name this Roman emperor, succeeded by Hadrian, who brought Rome to its greatest extent.", "answer": "<b> Trajan</b>", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "A revolt in this region began after fears it would lose the toleration granted to it in the \u201cLetter of Majesty\u201d of Rudolf II; that revolt featured an early capture of Pilsen by the forces of Ernst von Mansfeld. A ruler of this region, Frederick the Winter King, was defeated by Count Tilly at the Battle of White Mountain near its capital, which was earlier the site of an incident in which 2 Catholic ambassadors were tossed out of a window. For ten points, name this Czech region whose capital is Prague.", "answer": "<b> Bohemia</b> (prompt on anything related to Czech land before \u201cCzech\u201d is read, with the exception of \u201cCzechoslovakia;\u201d that\u2019s wrong)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "A slave born on this man\u2019s estate attempted the largest slave escape in American history, the Pearl Incident; that man, Paul Jennings, was one of over a hundred slaves belonging to this man. The wife of this man is often credited with saving a portrait of George Washington from the during the burning of DC; that woman, Dolley, moved with this man to the White House after her husband was elected president in 1808. For ten points, name this Virginian who served as the fourth president of the United States.", "answer": "James<b> Madison</b> Jr.", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "A town on the east bank of this river that is home to The Bend Motorsport Park is known as Tailem Bend. Albury and Wodonga are major population centers along this river that is one of the major inflows of Lake Alexandrina. The Murumbidgee River is a tributary of this river that flows through the Snowy Mountains. This river forms a large basin in its country\u2019s southeast with the Darling River. For ten points, name this longest river in Australia.", "answer": "<b> Murray</b> River", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "This man issued numerous telegraphs to \u201ccousin Willy\u201d to avoid war during the July Crisis. Sergei Witte advised this man to enact legal reforms in order to stay in power, even though this man\u2019s popularity had plummeted when his soldiers fired on father Georgy Gapon\u2019s protesters on Bloody Sunday. This man issued the October Manifesto in an attempt to pacify disgruntled workers but was soon overthrown in the October Revolution by Lenin\u2019s communists. For ten points, name the final tsar of Russia.", "answer": "<b> Nicholas II</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "Party of Thomas Jefferson that won the election.", "answer": "<b> Democratic Republican</b>s (do not prompt on partial answers) (2) Second president who lost the election, a Federalist from New England. ANSWER:<b> J</b>ohn<b> Adams</b> (prompt on Adams)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "Constitutional agreement in which slaves were counted as a namesake fraction of a person that helped decide the election.", "answer": "<b> Three-Fifths Compromise </b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "Candidate who tied with Jefferson in the Electoral College.", "answer": "Aaron<b> Burr </b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "Amendment passed after it that provided new procedures for electing a president and vice president.", "answer": "<b> 12</b>th Amendment", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "South Carolina Federalist vice presidential candidate.", "answer": "Charles Cotesworth<b> Pinckney </b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "Delaware Federalist who enabled Jefferson to win by leading abstentions.", "answer": "James<b> Bayard</b> Sr. Page 6", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "English king whose claim to the French throne caused it.", "answer": "<b> Edward III </b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "French heroine who was burned at the stake for witchcraft.", "answer": "<b> Joan of Arc</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "First battle won by English longbowmen, during which John of Bohemia was killed.", "answer": "Battle of<b> Crecy </b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "Battle won by Henry V on St. Crispin\u2019s Day.", "answer": "Battle of<b> Agincourt </b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "1340 naval battle in which the French navy was destroyed.", "answer": "Battle of<b> Sluys</b> [sloo-eece]", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "Peasant rebellion in northern France named for the term nobles used to refer to its participants.", "answer": "<b> Jacquerie </b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "French chronicler who described the history of the war from both sides.", "answer": "Jean<b> Froissart</b> Page 7", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "Egyptian peninsula on the Red Sea captured by Israel along with Gaza.", "answer": "<b> Sinai</b> Peninsula", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "Egyptian leader, an advocate of Pan-Arabism who nationalized the Suez Canal.", "answer": "Gamal Abdel<b> Nasser </b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "One eyed Israeli Minister of Defense who oversaw the capture of East Jerusalem.", "answer": "Moshe<b> Dayan </b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "Waterway that provided Israel\u2019s only access to the Red Sea; its closure by Egypt sparked the war.", "answer": "<b> Straits of Tiran </b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "Sudanese capital city where a namesake resolution that vowed continued belligerency with Israel was passed.", "answer": "<b> Khartoum </b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "American spy ship accidentally targeted by an Israeli airstrike.", "answer": "USS<b> Liberty </b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "Israeli general and future prime minister, victor of the decisive Battle of Abu Ageila against Egyptian forces.", "answer": "Ariel<b> Sharon </b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "Preemptive Israeli airstrike against the Egyptian Air Force that began the conflict.", "answer": "Operation<b> Focus</b> Page 8", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "<b>This body of water served as the debut ground for a weapon titled \u201cNo Alternative,\u201dwhich consisted of gunpowder hidden in reed mats that would then be dropped on the</b> <b>enemy. A naval battle in this body of water was fought over the town of (+)</b> <b>Nanchang</b> <b>and concluded when fire ships were successfully activated against the tower ships of Chen Youliang. This body of water was the site of the (*) </b> largest naval battle in history during the Red Turban Rebellion at the end of the Yuan dynasty. For ten points, name this lake in Jiangxi Province, the largest freshwater lake in China.", "answer": "Lake<b> Poyang</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "<b>In this city, Amedy Coulibaly killed four Jewish hostages during an attack on a kosher supermarket. The Kouachi brothers carried out an attack in this city in response to a series of (+) cartoons satirizing Mohammad; that attack on the</b><em><b> Charlie Hebdo</b></em><b> offices in this city occurred in the same year that airstrikes in Raqqa prompted on attack that saw 90 people killed in the (*)</b> Bataclan theater alone. That attack targeted a stadium where Francois Hollande was watching a sports match. For ten points, name this city that was targeted in a series of 2015 attacks.", "answer": "<b> Paris</b>", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {}, {"question": "<b>Alain Robert failed to climb this location in 1997 and 2007 before finally succeeding in 2009. The Suria Mall and Dewan Filharmonik are located at the bottom of this location, which was designed by (+) Cesar Pelli on the ground of the old Selangor Turf Club. A (*) </b>tube-in-tube design was used to build, for ten points, what tallest pair of twin towers in the world, a key piece of the skyline of Kuala Lumpur?", "answer": "<b> Petronas</b> Towers", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {}], "bonuses": []}